<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ข่าวไว</title>
    <link>https://www.facebook.com/share/19wfZDqCNY/?mibextid=wwXIfr</link>
    <description>ข่าวอัปเดตเร็ว ทันเหตุการณ์ รายชั่วโมง (แปลไทย+ภาพ)</description>
    <language>th-TH</language>

    <item>
      <title>Trump’s US$400 million White House ballroom can move ahead for now, judge rules</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3344786/trumps-us400-million-white-house-ballroom-can-move-ahead-now-judge-rules?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>A judge on Thursday ⁠declined to block US President Donald Trump from proceeding with the construction of a US$400 million White House ballroom to replace the demolished East Wing, finding that a challenge from preservationists did not meet the high bar for a preliminary injunction that would halt the project for now. US District Judge Richard Leon’s ruling came in a lawsuit by the National Trust</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 18:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4060b75627a3eed0b3a806584c2dfa64d36995cb</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/02/27/a9668ef7-a620-41c7-96fd-1dff82b4673b_e125e06a.jpg?itok=DKalS8pk&amp;v=1772130876" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>New York police arrest man after officers were pelted during snowball fight</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3344785/new-york-police-arrest-man-after-officers-were-pelted-during-snowball-fight?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>A 27-year-old man was arrested on Thursday after New York City police said officers were hurt when they were pelted with snow and ice during a massive snowball fight in Washington Square Park this week. The New York Police Department said in a brief social media post the man was arrested for “assaulting our officers”. A spokesperson for the department said it did not immediately have additional in</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 18:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8c0eca7de3789d2561a4d61c502c4aaed2d235ec</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/02/27/1c794093-ef5e-4dd2-87ba-099909cd5319_42203120.jpg?itok=KsdAxMTC&amp;v=1772129471" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hillary Clinton calls for Trump to testify as she faces US House Epstein panel</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3344784/hillary-clinton-calls-trump-testify-she-faces-us-house-epstein-panel?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>A Republican-led panel grilled Hillary Clinton on Thursday over her links to Jeffrey Epstein but she called for Donald Trump to testify about the president’s own connections to the convicted sex offender. Clinton told the congressional committee she had no information about Epstein’s crimes, did not recall encountering him and had never visited his island or flown on his plane, accusing the panel</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4d8ea9c68999f1f218dc0e48742dacc20d1fc783</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/02/27/cff75adc-ca6c-4c54-baf0-eda041494189_349c362b.jpg?itok=PL4Vc1gC&amp;v=1772126276" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Jersey votes to approve assisted dying as a similar UK bill stalls in House of Lords</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3344783/jersey-votes-approve-assisted-dying-similar-uk-bill-stalls-house-lords?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>A second British island voted on Thursday to approve assisted dying, as a similar bill that would allow terminally ill adults in England and Wales to choose to end their lives is bogged down in the British parliament. The bill, which requires the formality of approval by King Charles, would allow terminally ill residents who have lived in Jersey for more than a year and are expected to have less t</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 16:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">35c589cd6e69308153d3563d278dd1c42d5517dd</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/02/27/d81222e3-9f6d-4fb0-bdf8-8696bb5953d4_d2631d88.jpg?itok=dtk6sIm0&amp;v=1772127270" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Huawei targets global comeback with Mate 80 Pro smartphone, new smartwatch</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3344774/huawei-targets-global-comeback-mate-80-pro-smartphone-new-smartwatch?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Huawei Technologies is aiming for a major international comeback, with the overseas release of its latest flagship smartphone, the Mate 80 Pro, alongside a new smartwatch and the addition of a “wheelchair mode” to its wearable devices. Powered by the company’s self-designed, China-made Kirin 9030 Pro processor, the overseas version of its Mate 80 Pro handsets will run on the Android-based EMUI 15</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 16:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">c9f9a08509c6acc7462dad048111710b1891cd1e</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/02/26/f9426253-14b9-4fc9-8a8a-9e9a37d4616f_60392248.jpg?itok=9IASZW1w&amp;v=1772113396" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
