<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ข่าวไว</title>
    <link>https://www.facebook.com/share/19wfZDqCNY/?mibextid=wwXIfr</link>
    <description>ข่าวอัปเดตเร็ว ทันเหตุการณ์ รายชั่วโมง (แปลไทย+ภาพ)</description>
    <language>th-TH</language>

    <item>
      <title>Spain’s royals visit deadly train crash site as country mourns</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3340615/spains-royals-visit-deadly-train-crash-site-country-mourns?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Spain’s king and queen visited the site of the collision of two high-speed trains that killed at least 42 people on Tuesday, as the country began three days of national mourning. The country’s deadliest rail accident in more than a decade took place late on Sunday when a train operated by rail company Iryo, travelling from Malaga to Madrid, derailed near Adamuz in the southern Andalusia region. It</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">66bb87dbf58c2eaf5feeeb771bc196976627901f</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/01/21/cf2fd59d-6b68-48ce-b9d2-fd308a845582_97992f78.jpg?itok=xZNHfrTs&amp;v=1768938329" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Syria gives Kurds 4 days to accept integration, as US signals end of support</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3340614/syria-gives-kurds-4-days-accept-integration-us-signals-end-support?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Syria on Tuesday announced a ceasefire with Kurdish forces it ‌has seized swathes of territory from in the northeast and gave them four days to agree on integrating into the central state, which their main ally, the US, urged them to accept. The lightning government advances in recent days and the apparent withdrawal of US support for the continued holding of territory by the Syrian Democratic For</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">e9302791816d993ccbf421c5a4a32c94ac6682f6</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/01/21/af142b2e-00b4-454e-938c-2c08dacf7187_3a5c88af.jpg?itok=LaMzLtGF&amp;v=1768934957" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Greenland PM warns islanders to prepare for possible US invasion</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3340613/greenland-pm-warns-islanders-prepare-possible-us-invasion?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Greenland’s prime minister said the Arctic island’s population and its authorities need to start preparing for a possible military invasion, even as it remains an unlikely scenario, as US President Donald Trump continues to threaten taking over the territory. “It’s not likely there will be a military conflict, but it can’t be ruled out,” Prime Minister Jens-Frederik Nielsen said at a press confere</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8c8a995b43dae1e5be9e38f7535a7afbfec01ece</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/01/21/4eeb9abd-ac22-429a-94ea-332240970065_872dd70f.jpg?itok=pTQNHp4I&amp;v=1768933154" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Macron urges EU to hit back against Trump’s threats: ‘brutalisation of the world’</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3340612/brutalisation-world-macron-urges-europe-hit-back-against-trumps-threats?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Europe must respond to US threats over Greenland and China’s industrial excesses, or else “passively accept … vassalisation and bloc politics”, French President Emmanuel Macron warned in a speech at Davos on Tuesday. Macron warned of the “brutalisation of the world”, as he urged the use of the EU’s most powerful trade weapon in response to US President Donald Trump’s threat to slap tariffs on Euro</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">0de3340a494a9b94b1e65e4dc70f370152c3b5a7</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/01/21/f92d2bf3-db49-45c6-a688-6e9dd1175d34_669d3db1.jpg?itok=r_M7VR_s&amp;v=1768930741" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Canada plans for US invasion scenario as Trump posts ‘takeover’ map: report</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3340611/canada-plans-us-invasion-scenario-trump-posts-takeover-map-report?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>The Canadian military has developed a model response to a US invasion, the Globe and Mail reported on Tuesday, as US President Donald Trump again muses online about a takeover of Canada. Citing two unnamed senior government officials, the paper said the Canadian response model centres on insurgency-style tactics, like those used in Afghanistan by fighters who resisted Soviet and later US forces. T</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8c2685871dbee0bfe82c08c9404d1a00b994a940</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/01/20/5850f922-3de1-42e9-856c-c408464df5f3_acd15157.jpg?itok=YXpYff5t&amp;v=1768925347" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
