<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ข่าวไว</title>
    <link>https://www.facebook.com/share/19wfZDqCNY/?mibextid=wwXIfr</link>
    <description>ข่าวอัปเดตเร็ว ทันเหตุการณ์ รายชั่วโมง (แปลไทย+ภาพ)</description>
    <language>th-TH</language>

    <item>
      <title>ICE releases detained Filipino after ‘unreasonable failures of care’</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3343654/ice-releases-detained-filipino-after-unreasonable-failures-care?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>A Filipino man awaiting the result of a deportation order has been released from Tacoma’s Northwest ICE Processing Centre following a federal court order that called the man’s detention unconstitutionally “punitive”. US District Judge Tana Lin granted the release requested in Greggy Sorio’s habeas corpus petition on Friday, saying the Tacoma detention centre’s “unreasonable treatment” of Sorio bro</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 20:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">eba62a71cc491885dec9314e6b7394280989ca69</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/02/16/1980c76f-475d-4676-bc72-5cf539ad00a2_204256d9.jpg?itok=dzr9R6GE&amp;v=1771187145" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Trump’s border tsar Homan says ‘small’ security force will remain in Minnesota</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3343653/trumps-border-tsar-homan-says-small-security-force-will-remain-minnesota?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>White House border tsar Tom Homan said on Sunday that more than 1,000 immigration agents have left Minnesota’s Twin Cities area and hundreds more will depart in the days ahead as part of the Trump administration’s drawdown of its immigration enforcement surge. A “small” security force will stay for a short period to protect remaining immigration agents and will respond “when our agents are out and</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 19:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">e2d4c9656494f400a53594b6dd33320360face31</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/02/16/9013d6fe-8f6f-4a3b-9163-c939fe63d7f3_49782f9e.jpg?itok=hZw7vp3r&amp;v=1771181849" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Israel will begin contentious West Bank land registration in new step to deepen control</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3343652/israel-will-begin-contentious-west-bank-land-registration-new-step-deepen-control?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Israel will begin a contentious land regulation process in a large part of the occupied West Bank, which could result in Israel gaining control over wide swathes of the area for future development, according to a government decision on Sunday. It paves the way for the resumption of “settlement of land title” processes, which had been frozen in the West Bank since the Middle East war in 1967. It me</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 18:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">5a60cc2f6f7ed584d7fcafc7d739fda6fbc45857</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/02/16/971be426-853e-41a2-94dc-e1abfa7adc38_f18225d2.jpg?itok=UmDdFfIN&amp;v=1771179651" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>US ‘not disputing’ a ‘troubling’ European report on Navalny poisoning, Rubio says</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3343650/us-not-disputing-troubling-european-report-navalny-poisoning-rubio-says?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>US Secretary of State Marco Rubio said on Sunday that Washington is “not disputing” a report by five European countries that imprisoned Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny was fatally poisoned with a rare frog “toxin”. Rubio said the report released on Saturday by Britain, France, Germany, the Netherlands and Sweden was “very troubling”. Britain, which has outright blamed Russia for Navalny’s</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:16:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">e7893904d086ca5fd00cf64ca3ae7201f868493d</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/02/16/668ba2df-be7d-45c5-9ac5-ff43b9a055c8_eac7d243.jpg?itok=utfpyuz2&amp;v=1771175673" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Abuse survivor Pelicot says mindsets need to change in fight against sexual violence</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3343646/abuse-survivor-pelicot-says-mindsets-need-change-fight-against-sexual-violence?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Mindsets need to change in the fight against sexual violence, according to Gisele Pelicot, who was repeatedly drugged, abused and offered to strangers for rape by her then husband over nearly 10 years. “I believe this can only be achieved through education and through respect and empathy for one another,” the 73-year-old French woman told the news portal of German public broadcaster ZDF in an inte</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 16:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">19cba1c2a618e9dcce9f13eea4f18a156f57f676</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2026/02/16/8a315d4c-33a0-48f6-a7e1-794b8c13a574_8dbcf8a8.jpg?itok=ft_Fgueq&amp;v=1771173275" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
