<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ข่าวไว</title>
    <link>https://www.facebook.com/share/19wfZDqCNY/?mibextid=wwXIfr</link>
    <description>ข่าวอัปเดตเร็ว ทันเหตุการณ์ รายชั่วโมง (แปลไทย+ภาพ)</description>
    <language>th-TH</language>

    <item>
      <title>North Korea fires warning over Japan’s ambition for nuclear weapons</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3337210/north-korea-fires-warning-over-japans-ambition-nuclear-weapons?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>North Korea said Japan’s ambition for possession of nuclear weapons should ⁠be “thoroughly curbed”, state media KCNA reported on Sunday. Japan is showing the intention to possess nuclear weapons explicitly by ‍saying it needs to review ‍the three non-nuclear principles, KCNA said, citing a commentary of ‌North Korea’s foreign policy official. Japan began making such ‍comments actively as soon as t</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">877c293f2487af7d90ddbb383f29f9d73397ec18</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/21/0db2444d-4753-4327-9f09-44759832e4d4_775d49ad.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong and Singapore landlords embrace flex offices as multinationals reshape demand</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3336733/hong-kong-and-singapore-landlords-embrace-flex-offices-multinationals-reshape-demand?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Landlords in Hong Kong and Singapore are expected to continue allocating space to flexible office operators as multinational corporations reshape the sector’s risk profile and fuel long-term demand, according to industry experts. A major driver behind this shift is the rapid change in who uses flexible workspaces. Global companies now represented 41 per cent of Asia-Pacific flex office users, the</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">d6345ee27c54b1774838118f247ce14067260efb</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/17/2c18b9ce-6668-4461-8a4f-8d20b02369c9_7328805f.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>China eases visa rules for India, tapping into US$21.6 billion travel market</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3337089/china-eases-visa-rules-india-tapping-us216-billion-travel-market?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Beijing and New Delhi have taken another step towards normalising economic ties after a five-year rift, as China moves to introduce a simplified visa process for Indian nationals that could help it tap India’s fast-growing travel market. The Chinese embassy in New Delhi said earlier this month that Indian citizens would be able to apply for visas online from December 22, sparing them time-consumin</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b959e321a8c9650b2dfc98670f3310e9652c6cde</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/19/c396ceef-640c-4dda-82d8-d71d466adc9f_3f3e27d2.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>From Labubu to blockbuster films, was 2025 the year China’s soft power went mainstream?</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3335844/labubu-blockbuster-films-was-2025-year-chinas-soft-power-went-mainstream?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Catch up on some of SCMP’s biggest stories about China’s soft power this year. If you would like to see more of our reporting, please consider subscribing. 1. Labubu, soft power of a stealthy ‘ugly-cute’ sort, takes on America The Chinese-made dolls, a playful global megahit, give Beijing an opportunity to make inroads into deep US distrust. 2. ‘Huge shift’: why learning Mandarin is losing its app</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9eeac66eb67e286df127988f5885eab45a22909c</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/10/52aa94dc-f92f-4679-87a3-81a9dd959ff3_06e07862.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>In eastern China, ancient ruins are pushing back the date of Yangtze delta’s earliest cities</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3337191/eastern-china-ancient-ruins-are-pushing-back-date-yangtze-deltas-earliest-cities?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Chinese archaeologists unearthing the ruins of the earliest known settlement in the Yangtze River Delta say water management may have been the origin of ancient “cities” in the area. Researchers began large-scale excavations of the Doushan site in Wuxi in the eastern province of Jiangsu in July last year, dating the city to about 6,000 years ago. Previously, the oldest urban site in the delta area</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">e4fda5454ff954cf9600521cca50927f0a4153a1</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/20/8117f6f4-32ba-4786-bf9a-5d3d6920af72_37002f2b.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
