<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>ข่าวไว</title>
    <link>https://www.facebook.com/share/19wfZDqCNY/?mibextid=wwXIfr</link>
    <description>ข่าวอัปเดตเร็ว ทันเหตุการณ์ รายชั่วโมง (แปลไทย+ภาพ)</description>
    <language>th-TH</language>

    <item>
      <title>India overtakes Japan as world’s fourth largest economy, eyes top 3 by 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3338156/india-overtakes-japan-worlds-4th-largest-economy-eyes-top-3-2026?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>India has overtaken Japan as the world’s fourth-largest economy – and officials hope to pass Germany within three years, the government’s end-of-year economic review calculates. Official confirmation however depends on data due in 2026 when final annual gross domestic product figures are released, with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) suggesting India will cross over Japan next year. “India i</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 09:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">fce4018ab72ea1a3ecc658750681d300896574dc</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/30/d336b6a3-acfc-43be-bc6a-e6ff3fca074d_d6ec98c9.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>In a year of conflict, global science cooperation has shown the way</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/opinion/world-opinion/article/3338041/year-conflict-global-science-cooperation-has-shown-way?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>เมื่อมองย้อนกลับไปในปี 2025 เราอาจได้รับความชอบธรรมในการเรียกมันว่า annus horribilis สำหรับโลกดูเหมือนว่าข่าวร้ายจะไม่มีที่สิ้นสุด: สงครามในยูเครนการทำลายกาซาการโจมตีด้วยการก่อการร้ายในออสเตรเลียและความพ่ายแพ้ทางเศรษฐกิจและการเมืองที่สำคัญที่หลายประเทศในเอเชียและทั่วโลกต้องเผชิญทั้งหมดนี้วาดภาพที่ค่อนข้างน่ากลัวอย่างไรก็ตามมีมากกว่าความหวังที่ริบหรี่</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7e91dac879fd8c5006c41a4ebcee0ff56796f3a3</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/29/a423e7ed-3183-4467-9ee3-7dabfb0ff8e6_8a627b38.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong private subsidised flat scheme suffers new blow as Tung Chung site reassigned</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3338151/hong-kong-private-subsidised-flat-scheme-suffers-new-blow-tung-chung-site-reassigned?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>A residential site, originally earmarked for a pilot scheme allowing private developers to build subsidised homes, will be allocated to Hong Kong’s second-largest public housing provider, marking the latest setback for a venture aimed at boosting the supply of affordable flats. The government said on Tuesday that the site in Tung Chung, originally designated for the Private Subsidised Sale Flat Pi</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">65420a60164baf579a1900bf7d5555875b0d58bf</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/30/29e36897-7186-44bf-8ced-021f1854b7ee_11aacead.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong authorities praise schools for major progress in fostering patriotism</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3338146/hong-kong-authorities-praise-schools-major-progress-fostering-patriotism?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>Hong Kong’s education authorities have commended schools for making significant progress in fostering patriotism among students over the last academic year as compared with the past, with national education now steadily woven into daily teaching and learning. The report, released on Monday, also highlighted teachers’ stronger grasp of national security education, enabling them to guide students on</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b48ed75e523b218c034cf5d406831c0fee4be1a1</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/30/d03196aa-542b-48c6-bdd9-36f2d85721d4_31705b87.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>300,000 Hongkongers to be offered free hepatitis B screenings in early 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3338148/300000-hongkongers-be-offered-free-hepatitis-b-screenings-early-2026?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>ชาวฮ่องกงประมาณ 300,000 คนจะได้รับการตรวจคัดกรองไวรัสตับอักเสบบีฟรีในช่วงต้นปีหน้าเนื่องจากเมืองมีเป้าหมายที่จะบรรลุเป้าหมายระหว่างประเทศเพื่อกำจัดโรคที่เป็นภัยต่อสุขภาพของประชาชนภายในปี 2030 โครงการตรวจคัดกรองจะดำเนินการควบคู่ไปกับมาตรการอื่นๆของเจ้าหน้าที่ในการรับมือกับโรคไวรัสตับอักเสบเนื่องจากฮ่องกงได้เปิดตัวแผนปฏิบัติการไวรัสตับอักเสบในอีกห้าปีข้างหน้า “เราสามารถพูดได้ว่า</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">f6b34f46753e085784db01b0c7ce43e4c241eee5</guid>
      <enclosure url="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1280x720/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/30/08bd91bb-18c1-4fca-9ddd-e353d9026018_bcce0503.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
